Camille Cobb

Postdoctoral Researcher, CyLab Security and Privacy Institute, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA 15213, USA ccobb@andrew.cmu.edu • www.camillec.com • Twitter: @camPossible

RESEARCH **SUMMARY**

I am broadly interested in computer Security & Privacy and HCI. My thesis research focused on understanding how users' expectations of privacy may be violated by other users of social and communication applications, without leveraging special privileges or technical skills. My current research, conducted in my role as a postdoctoral researcher collaborating with Lujo Bauer at CMU, considers the privacy impacts of smart home technology on "incidental users" - people who come into contact with other people's smart home devices, possibly having their data collected without their awareness or consent.

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Computer Science and Engineering	2019
Master of Science (M.S.), Computer Science and Engineering	2014
Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Virginia, USA	
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Computer Science	2012
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Physics	2012

Minor, German

HONORS/AWARDS National Research Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship (2014)

CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Award Honorable Mention (2012)

Other Research Awards

Winner of USENIX Security & Privacy Lightning Talk (2018)

Scholarships

UW CSE Educator's Fellowship National Merit Scholar Virginia Foundation of Independent Colleges Grant RE Lee Scholarship Holbrook Scholarship

Other Awards

National Honor Society Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society Phi Eta Sigma Honor Society Sigma Pi Sigma Physics Honor Society W&L Physics Sophomore Student of the Year

PEER-REVIEWED **PUBLICATIONS**

"A Privacy-Focused Systematic Analysis of Online Status Indicators." Camille Cobb, Lucy Simko, Tadayoshi Kohno, Alexis Hiniker. PETS 2020) Jul 2020.

"User Experiences with Online Status Indicators." Camille Cobb, Lucy Simko, Tadayoshi Kohno, Alexis Hiniker. CHI 2020) Apr 2020.

"User-to-User Privacy in Social and Communications Applications." Camille Cobb. Doctoral Dissertation) Jun 2019.

"How Public Is My Private Life? Privacy in Online Dating." Camille Cobb, Tadayoshi Kohno. 26th International World Wide Web Conference (WWW '17) Apr 2018.

"Computer security for data collection technologies." Camille Cobb*, Samuel Sudar*, Nicholas Reiter, Richard Anderson, Franziska Roesner, and Tadayoshi Kohno. Development Engineering, Volume 3, 2018 (available Dec 2017). Journal version of prior work presented at ICTD '16.

"Computer Security for Data Collection Technologies." <u>Camille Cobb</u>*, Samuel Sudar*, Nicholas Reiter, Richard Anderson, Franziska Roesner, and Tadayoshi Kohno. International Conference on Information & Communication Technologies and Development (ICTD '16) Jun 2016. Journal version appears in Development Engineering 2018 (full publication information above).

"Designing for the deluge: understanding & supporting the distributed, collaborative work of crisis volunteers." <u>Camille Cobb</u>, Ted McCarthy, Annuska Perkins, Ankitha Bharadwaj, Jared Comis, Brian Do, and Kate Starbird. 17th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW '14) Feb 2014.

"Leveraging user-privilege classification to customize usage-based statistical models of web applications." Sara Sprenkle, <u>Camille Cobb</u>, and Lori Pollock. Fifth International Conference on Software Testing, Verification and Validation (ICST '12) Apr 2012.

STUDENTS

Clemend Zhong, UW Allen School Undergraduate (First year)

Jul 2018 – Feb 2019 **Kayla Butler**, UW Allen School Undergraduate (First/Second year)

Jul 2017 – Jul 2018

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Washington, Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering

Teaching Assistant, CSE 564 (Graduate Computer Security and Privacy)	Winter 2018
Teaching Assistant, CSE 484 (Undergraduate Computer Security and Privacy)	Fall 2016
Group Leader for a UW HCDE Directed Research Group	2013-2014
Student Assistant for Introductory CS Lab at Washington and Lee	Winter 2010

OUTREACH AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Education, Diversifying Participation in Computer Science

Guest Speaker at CSE Summer Camp and Engineering Exploration Program	2018
Security and Privacy lightning talk for Undergraduate Summer Research Semina	ar 2018
Mentor to undergraduate women in CSE	2016-2017
Volunteer for UW CSE Computing Open House	2014, 2015, 2017
Mentor and Mentor Coordinator for the Paul Allen Computing Challenge	2014 and 2015
Volunteer undergraduate tutor for CSE 312, Foundations of Computing II	2015
Computer science outreach presentation at Seattle middle school	2012
Women in Technology and Science Physics Chair (W&L)	2009-2010
Women in Math and Science Member (W&L)	2010-2012

Department Service

Service to the department (now the Paul G. Allen School) through coordinating weekly social events (2013–2014) and contributing to department-wide networking, outreach, recruitment, diversity and inclusion, and social events.

Other

Invited Participant at IEEE Workshop on IoT Security Building Code	May 2017
Volunteer at Greyhound Dog Rescue	2013-2014
Volunteer at Therapeutic Horseback Riding Facility	2008-2012

PRESENTATIONS

Conference Talks

<u>Camille Cobb</u>, Lucy Simko, Tadayoshi Kohno, Alexis Hiniker. "A Privacy-Focused Systematic Analysis of Online Status Indicators." July 2020 at PoPETS.

<u>Camille Cobb</u>, Tadayoshi Kohno. "How Public Is My Private Life? Privacy in Online Dating." April 2017 at WWW.

<u>Camille Cobb</u>, Ted McCarthy, Annuska Perkins, Ankitha Bharadwaj, Jared Comis, Brian Do, and Kate Starbird. "Designing for the deluge: understanding & supporting the distributed, collaborative work of crisis volunteers." Feb 2014 at CSCW.

Invited Talks

<u>Camille Cobb</u>. "Privacy in Online Dating." November 2017 at Seattle Science Slam to a general audience.

^{*}Denotes equal contributions, listed in alphabetical order

Lightning Talks

<u>Camille Cobb.</u> "Presentations of Security and Privacy on Television." August 2018 at USENIX Security & Privacy.

Poster Presentations

<u>Camille Cobb.</u> "Exploring Text-Based Analysis of Test-Case Dependencies of Web Applications." SIGCSE Student Research Competition. March 2012.

<u>Camille Cobb</u> and Sara Sprenkle. "Exploring Text-Based Analysis of Test-Case Dependencies of Web Applications. CRA/CDC NSF Site Visit." September 2011.

<u>Camille Cobb</u> and Sara Sprenkle. "Toward a User-Session Dependency Model for Automatically Testing Web Applications." Tapia Celebration of Diversity in Computing. April 2011.

Katie Baldwin, <u>Camille Cobb</u>, Carrie Hopkins, Sara Sprenkle, and Lori Pollock. "Exploring Data Models for Automatically Generating Tests for Web Applications." Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing. September 2009.

WORK Academic Work Experience

Postdoctoral Researcher in CMU's CyLab

July 2019-Present

Industry Work Experience

Software Engineering Intern with Google's Geo-Oceans Team

Summer 2013 and 2014

Undergraduate Research Experiences

"Medical Process Visualization." DREU with Lori Clarke at UMass Amherst. (Summer 2011)

"Dynamic Analysis of Web Application Access Logs for Software Testing." CREU with Sara Sprenkle at W&L. (2010-2011)

"Investigating Data Models for Automatically Generating Tests for Web Applications." DREU with Sara Sprenkle and Lori Pollock at University of Delaware. (Summer 2009)

"Exploring Text-Based Analysis of Test-Case Dependencies of Web Applications" Senior honors thesis with Sara Sprenkle at W&L. (2011-2012)

REFERENCES Lujo Bauer

Professor, Electrical & Computer Engineering and Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University lbauer@andrew.cmu.edu

Tadayoshi Kohno

Professor, Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering, University of Washington yoshi@cs.washington.edu

Alexis Hiniker

Assistant Professor of Human Computer Interaction, Information School, University of Washington alexisr@uw.edu